Doctoral Graduation Ceremony - ETH Zurich
حفل منح درجة الدكتوراه — المعهد الفدرالي السويسري للتكنولوجيا في زيورخ
Once Upon A PhD - Hong Xu
كان يا ما كان، دكتور في الفلسفة — هونغ شو
Really great! Yes! - Prof. Springmann, Rector of ETH Zurich
ممتاز! نعم! — البروفيسور سبرينغمان، رئيس ETH زيورخ
Doctorate Award - Mr. Dr. Hong Xu
تم منح درجة الدكتوراه — الدكتور هونغ شو
One, two, three, four! ETH Big Band
واحد، اثنان، ثلاثة، أربعة! — فرقة ETH الموسيقية
I wish you all the very best, take care and have a lovely party tonight, thank you for being here!
أتمنى لكم كل الخير، اعتنوا بأنفسكم، واستمتعوا بهذه الليلة الجميلة. شكرًا لحضوركم!
In my life, I wanted to see so much, give so much, do so much, and believe in tomorrow
كنت دائمًا أرغب في رؤية الكثير، والعطاء الكثير، والقيام بالكثير، والإيمان بالغد.
Why not play the hero of a book that goes far, that loses its way
لماذا لا ألعب دور بطل في رواية يسافر بعيدًا، حتى لو تاه في الطريق؟
In life, I will do everything to not be the one who speaks for nothing
سأبذل قصارى جهدي حتى لا أكون من يتحدث عبثًا.
I will go to the end of my dreams
سأسعى وراء أحلامي حتى النهاية.
Oh, how beautiful the earth is, under its sun
آه، كم هي جميلة الأرض تحت شمسها.
Hair in the wind, I will cross all the seas
بشعر يتطاير، سأعبر كل البحار.
Without any regret, without baggage and with a heart of stone
دون ندم، دون أمتعة، بقلب من حجر.
I will shout from the rooftops of the world, to the endless horizon of my dreams
سأصرخ من فوق أسطح العالم نحو أفق أحلامي اللامحدود.
Don’t cry, give me your wings, you will write to me that you love me
لا تبكي، أعطني جناحيك، اكتب لي أنك تحبني.
That life is made only to be the one I describe in my poems
أن الحياة وجدت لتكون كما في أشعاري.
Don’t cry, I have no trouble, just enough to make my life
لا تبكي، ليس لدي ألم — فقط ما أحتاجه لبناء حياتي.
As long as four stars light the way of the first
طالما أربع نجوم تضيء الطريق للنجم الأول،
I will journey to the farthest reaches of the earth, and pursue the endless horizon of my dreams
سأسافر إلى أقصى زوايا الأرض،追ًا لأفق أحلامي اللامحدود.
[Filmed by Hong Xu during his doctoral studies in Switzerland]
[تصوير هونغ شو خلال دراسته للدكتوراه في سويسرا]
I do not flee, I leave, I run, I fall, I fly and go toward my destiny
أنا لا أهرب — أنا أذهب. أركض، أسقط، وأطير إلى قدري.
As if my heart could not stay still in this uncertain world
وكأن قلبي لا يستطيع البقاء في هذا العالم المتغير.
In life, I will do everything to not be the one who speaks for nothing
سأبذل قصارى جهدي حتى لا أكون من يتحدث عبثًا.
I will pursue the endless horizon of my dreams
سأسعى وراء أفق أحلامي اللامحدود.
Oh, how beautiful the earth is under its sun
آه، كم هي جميلة الأرض تحت شمسها.
Hair in the wind, I will cross all the seas
بشعر يتطاير، سأعبر كل البحار.
Without any regret, without baggage and with a heart of stone
دون ندم، دون أمتعة، بقلب من حجر.
I will shout from the rooftops of the world, to the endless horizon of my dreams
سأصرخ من فوق أسطح العالم نحو أفق أحلامي اللامحدود.
Don’t cry, give me your wings, you will write to me that you love me
لا تبكي، أعطني جناحيك، اكتب لي أنك تحبني.
That life is made only to be the one I describe in my poems
أن الحياة وجدت لتكون كما في أشعاري.
Don’t cry, I have no trouble, just enough to make my life
لا تبكي، ليس لدي ألم — فقط ما أحتاجه لبناء حياتي.
As long as four stars light the way of the first
طالما أربع نجوم تضيء الطريق للنجم الأول،
Don’t cry, give me your wings, you will write to me that you love me
لا تبكي، أعطني جناحيك، اكتب لي أنك تحبني.
That life is made only to be the one I describe in my poems
أن الحياة وجدت لتكون كما في أشعاري.
Don’t cry, I have no trouble, just enough to make my life
لا تبكي، ليس لدي ألم — فقط ما أحتاجه لبناء حياتي.
As long as four stars light the way of the first
طالما أربع نجوم تضيء الطريق للنجم الأول،
I will journey to the farthest reaches of the earth
سأسافر إلى أقصى زوايا الأرض.
I will pursue the endless horizon of my dreams
سأسعى وراء أفق أحلامي اللامحدود.
[French Cover - Au bout de mes rêves by FLD5 / Original Version - Fleet of Time by Kubert Leung]
[نسخة غنائية فرنسية — *Au bout de mes rêves* FLD5 / الأصل — *Fleet of Time* لـ Cubert Leung]
[Filmed by Hong Xu during his doctoral studies in Switzerland]
[تصوير هونغ شو خلال دراسته للدكتوراه في سويسرا]
[The End - Once Upon A PhD]
[النهاية — كان يا ما كان، دكتور في الفلسفة]